创世之初 冥冥之中
In the beginning, there was darkness,
随着一声爆炸
and then, bang--
诞生了无尽膨胀的
giving birth to an endless expanding existence
时间 空间和物质
of time, space, and matter.
每一天 新的发现都在揭秘这个诡异
Every day, new discoveries are unlocking the mysterious,
震撼 神秘莫测的
the mind-blowing, the deadly secrets
地方 - 我们所谓的《宇宙》
of a place we call "The Universe."
如果你认为土星是唯一的环状行星 就大错特错了
If you thought Saturn was the only ringed planet, think again.
围绕太阳的四颗巨行星都有环状系统
All four of the giant planets orbiting the sun have ring systems.
甚至冥王星都可能具有星环
Even Pluto might have rings.
航天器穿越它们将会是致命的
Flying a spacecraft through them would be deadly.
这些颗粒围绕土星的速度是子弹的15倍
These particles orbit Saturn at 15 times the speed of a rifle bullet.
因此要发现它们 星环猎手必须将科技推至极致
So to find them, ring hunters must push technology to the limit.
那是个挑战
It was a challenge,
就像是拍摄躲在煤仓里黑猫照片一样
like taking a picture of a cat in a coal bin.
从宇宙外围
From the outer reaches of the cosmos,
到我们自家后院惊人的星环系统
to a surprising ring system in our own backyard,
这就是 - 搜寻环状行星之旅
this is "The Hunt for Ringed Planets."
--==本影片由 CMCT 团队 荣誉出品==--
更多精彩影视 请访问 http://www.hdcmct.com
影片压制:暮云春树  字幕来源：HDC字幕组 调校：晴天 招募Q号: 76846146
历史频道 - 宇宙 第4季第5集 搜索环状行星
The History Channel - The Universe s04e05 Hunt For Ringed Planets
这是距离太阳的第六颗行星
This is the sixth planet from the Sun.
认不出它了吧？
Don't recognize it?
那是因为有东西给漏了
That's because something's missing.
没有了其标志性的星环 土星只不过是又一颗行星
Without its iconic rings, Saturn would be just another planet.
它们是其美貌的关键所在
They are the key to its beauty.
通过望远镜观看土星环的兴奋难以言表
The exhilaration of seeing Saturn's rings through the telescope can't be overstated.
它简直是叹为观止
It is just such a marvelous sight.
人们惊叹土星环
People have been in awe of Saturn's rings
自伽利略在1610年首次发现它们以来一直如此
since Galileo first discovered them in the year 1610.
从那时起 天文学家就将他们对这颗最早的环状行星
Since then, astronomers have applied everything they know
所了解的一切用来搜寻更多的环状行星
about the original ringed planet in their hunt for more.
不过我们凝视土星环时 我们究竟看到了什么？
But when we gaze at Saturn's rings, what exactly are we looking at?
地球上完美的景观掩盖了混乱的场景
The perfection viewed from Earth masks a scene of chaos.
物体相互碰撞 彼此推搡
Things are bumping into each other and spattering off of one another.
所以那是个混乱冰凉的乱石场
And so it's a very sort of chaotic, icy rubble field,
一起围绕着土星运转
all moving together around Saturn.
随着时间的推移 星环猎手发现不只是一个环
Over time, ring hunters found not just one ring,
而是有一个七条主带的系列围绕着土星的赤道
but a series of seven main bands around Saturn's equator.
土星环的首个详尽的视图
The first really detailed views of Saturn's rings
出自1980年前后的旅行者号探测器
came from the Voyager spacecraft around 1980,
那些照片令人咋舌
and those photographs were truly breathtaking.
每个环都是由数以万亿计的颗粒构成
Each ring is made of trillions of particles,
从尘埃颗粒带大如房子的物体 大小不等
ranging in size from a grain of dust to something as big as a house.
它们不难看到
They were easy to see
因为它们是太阳系里最亮的星环
since they're the brightest rings in the solar system.
它们闪闪发光是因为它们非常紧凑挤在一起
They glisten because they are so tightly packed
因为块体高度反光
and because the chunks are highly reflective,
几乎是100%的冰块
being almost 100% ice.
如果你位于土星环的下方
If you were positioned below Saturn's rings,
但就在几百码的地方
but a few hundred yards away,
你就会看到这个广泛分布的石块 冰球 雪球
you would see this vast expanse of boulders and ice balls, snowballs,
透过其中的一些地方 你会看到另一面的星星
and through some parts you could see stars on the other side,
但是其他部分非常稠密 是不透明的
but other parts would be so thick that they would be opaque.
那将是个美妙的景象
It would be a wonderful sight.
天文学家命名七个主环
Astronomers named the seven main rings
就用了字母表上的字母
simply by the letters of the alphabet,
不过是按照它们被发现的顺序
but in the order they were discovered:
A  B  C  D  E  F  最后1980年发现的 G
A, B, C, D, E, F, and the last, detected in 1980, G.
总之 星环猎手发现了一个星系
All told, ring hunters had found a system
展开成庞大的18万英里直径的范围
that sprawled a whopping 180,000 miles in diameter.
星环的边到边几乎是
The rings from edge to edge are
地球与月球距离的2/3左右
almost 2/3 or so as wide as the distance from the Earth to our own Moon,
所以说它们非常庞大
so they're quite vast.
然而难以置信的是 星环的单个平面
Yet incredibly, the rings form a single plane
是个薄片 平均不到30英尺
that is wafer thin, averaging less than 30 feet.
它们非常扁平
They're very flat.
就像是中央公园那样的一张纸
It's like a sheet of paper the size of Central Park.
然而这些美丽的结构也是动力十足的歹徒
But these beautiful structures are also turbo-charged hellions.
其中的冰粒在星球旁呼啸而过
Their icy particles scream around the planet
时速高达5 3万英里
at up to 53,000 miles per hour,
就像是永无尽头的宇宙赛车场上的赛车
like speeding cars on a never-ending cosmic race track.
在这样的高速情况下 星环无疑会让
At these high velocities, the rings spell certain death
胆敢冒险靠近的任何东西命丧九泉
for anything daring to venture too close.
这些围绕土星的颗粒的速度是子弹的15倍
These particles orbit Saturn at 15 times the speed of a rifle bullet.
一块两英寸宽的东西可以对航天器撞出致命的窟窿
A chunk just two inches wide could blast a deadly hole in a spacecraft.
这些颗粒就像是速度疯狂的赛车
The particles are like race cars at mind-bending speeds.
然而就像这些赛车一样 环中的每个颗粒
Yet like these cars, each particle in the ring
的速度几乎与周围颗粒的速度相等
is moving at almost the same speed as the ones around it.
但是由于它们的速度和方向并不完全匹配
But since their speeds and directions don't match exactly
有时会被周围的力量所改变
and are sometimes changed by forces around them,
冰块会无情的碰撞和推挤 -
the icy chunks relentlessly bump and jostle--
就像激烈竞争中的赛车一般
just like race cars in the heat of competition.
多数碰撞是低强度的 没有多大影响
Most bumps are low impact and don't have much effect.
但是有时 一个碰撞可以将一个颗粒撞入太空
But at times, a crash can send a particle hurtling into space.
是什么让这些疾飞的冰球保持在圆环中的呢？
What keeps these rocketing ice balls in a ring?
土星强大的引力
The powerful force of Saturn's gravitational pull.
如果你突然拿走土星的引力
If you suddenly took Saturn's gravity away,
环状颗粒就会四处飞离
then the ring particles would go flying off
它们会和土星同时消失
in the directions that they were going at the moment that Saturn disappeared.
反之 行星的引力
Instead, the gravity of the planet
和颗粒的速度处于理想的平衡
and the velocity of the particles are in perfect balance,
结果颗粒永远在坠落
so that the particles are eternally "falling,"
即弯曲向行星 但永远都不可能更加接近
or curving in, towards the planet, but never getting any closer.
不过土星不是唯一的引力源
But Saturn is not the only source of gravity.
环中的颗粒都有自己的引力
The particles in the rings have their own,
它们在坚持不懈地努力抱成一团
and it is relentlessly trying to pull them into a cluster
形成更大的物体 如小月球
to form something larger, like a small moon.
每一个颗粒都在吸引着其他的颗粒
Every particle is attracted to every other particle,
较大的颗粒具有较大的引力
and the more massive ones have a bigger pull,
你越靠近 引力就越大
and the closer you are the more the pull is.
不过颗粒的引力要对抗土星的引力
But the gravity of the particles works against the gravity of Saturn.
那是一场永恒的战争
It's an eternal war.
这场持续的战争 可以说是
There's this constant battle, if you like,
存在于努力将物体拉在一起的引力
between the force of gravity trying to pull things together,
环状颗粒的引力
gravity of the ring particles,
与努力将它们拆散的土星引力之间
and Saturn's gravity trying to tear them apart.
土星引力将颗粒相互拉开
Saturn's gravity pulls particles away from each other
那是由于在轨物体速度的普遍规律
because of a universal law about the speed of objects in orbit.
你离土星越近
The closer you are to Saturn,
你要跑得更快才能保持在轨道上
the more quickly you need to move to stay in orbit.
如果你跑得不快的话 就会掉入行星
If you're not moving really fast, you'll fall into the planet.
土星最里面的星环里的颗粒
Particles of Saturn's innermost ring
疾飞的速度远超过最外面星环里的颗粒的速度
tear around at more than 30,000 miles per hour faster
超出了有每小时3万英里
than those in the outermost ring.
即使一个冰块就比别人靠里面多一尺
Even if one icy chunk is just a foot closer than another,
也会在速度上有细微的差异
there will be a tiny difference in speed.
那种差异足以阻止颗粒呆在一起
That difference is enough to prevent the particles from staying together.
即使间隔很小的距离 里面的颗粒
Even over very small distances, the inside particles
也要比外面的颗粒跑得快
are moving faster than the outside particles,
它们沿着这些弧圈散布开
stretching them out along these ring arcs,
因此你永远都看不到星环凝聚成实体
so you'll never get the rings coalescing back into a solid body.
这种颗粒分组为小结构的没完没了的战争
This perpetual battle of particles grouping into small structures,
不断地分开重组
being pulled away and regrouping,
已经在星环里持续了有数百万乃至数十亿年了
has maintained the rings for millions, possibly billions of years.
它们在彼此推搡 相互碰撞
They're sort of jostling each other and bumping into each other,
感受着他们自己微弱的引力
feeling their own very, very weak gravity
不断形成短暂的结构 此消彼长
continuously forming transient structures, which come and go.
整个星环系统处在很好的平衡之中
The whole ring system is in a very nice balance.
引力的平衡保持着星环系统的稳定
The balance of gravity holds the ring system in place,
不过就是围绕行星的旋转运动
but it's the motion of spinning around the planet
创造了它们壮观的形态
that creates their breathtaking form.
我们来到这个披萨店里演示一下
We've come here to a pizzeria to show how
一个飞快旋转物体是如何自然形成薄圆盘的
the natural form for a very rapidly rotating object is a thin disk.
我们从一块皮萨面团开始
So we're starting out with a piece of pizza dough
还没有旋转 几乎就是一块面团
that's not spinning and is pretty much a round lump.
当面团抛起并转起来后
When the dough is thrown and is spun up,
它就自然变扁平成为很薄的碟状
it naturally flattens out into quite a very thin disk-like shape.
旋转产生的离心力把面团压扁了
The centrifugal force from the spinning causes the dough to flatten out.
同样的道理 土星环里的颗粒的快速旋转运动
For a similar reason, the rapid orbital motion
不妨这么说
of the particles in Saturn's rings, the spin, if you will,
土星环的自转使其形成了一个非常稳定
of Saturn's rings allows it to form into a very stable,
非常长寿 极薄的圆盘
very long-lived, extremely thin disk.
但真要是星环如此稳定 那为何它们
But if the rings are so stable, why did they disappear
在第一个星环猎手伽利略发现它们的两年后又消失了呢？
two years after the first ring hunter, Galileo, discovered them?
1610年 他进行了他对星环的首次观察
In 1610, he made his first observation of the rings,
星环通过他的原始望远镜
which, through his primitive telescope,
表现为行星两侧的圆环
appeared as circles on either side of the planet.
当他在1612年再次观察时 圆环不见了
When he looked again in 1612, the circles were gone.
伽利略一头雾水 不过这个谜团的答案
Galileo was baffled, but the answer to this mystery
对现代天文学家来说是显而易见的
is obvious to modern astronomers.
伽利略在第二年并未看到这些突出物
Galileo didn't see these protrusions the second year,
因为当时土星环几乎是边缘对着他的视线
because at that time Saturn's rings were nearly edge-on to his line of sight,
因此它们基本上是看不见了
and so they were essentially invisible.
边缘正对视线 30年里发生两回
An edge-on view occurs twice
这取决于土星围绕太阳的轨道
in the 30 years it takes Saturn to orbit the Sun.
星环表现出的角度在不断变化
The angle at which the rings are seen is constantly changing,
因为行星本身倾斜了27度
because the planet itself tilts 27 degrees.
这是土星
So this is Saturn,
它倾斜了27度 它正面对着我
and it's tilted 27 degrees, so it's facing me.
我可以从上面看到星环
I can see the rings from above.
土星移动了 现在到了这里
Saturn moves, so now is here,
我可以看到星环的侧影像一条笔直的细线
and I could see the rings in profile as a straight, thin line.
然后它移到了另一侧
Then it moves on the other side
你可以从下方看到星环
and you can see the ring from down below.
虽然伽利略之谜被后来的星环猎手给迅速解决了
While Galileo's mystery was swiftly resolved by later ring hunters,
但是土星最根本的问题之一
one of the most fundamental questions about Saturn
被激辩至今
is hotly debated to this day.
这些星环打哪而来？
Where did the rings come from?
那确实是星环科学里最大的难题
It's the biggest conundrum in ring science, really,
土星环的起源
the origin of Saturn's rings.
两种理论互不相让
Two theories vie for dominance.
一个认为星环的形成是紧随土星的诞生
One holds that the rings formed just after the birth of Saturn
是在45亿年前
4 1/2 billion years ago.
它们是旋流物质盘在形成行星后的残留物
They were the leftovers from the spinning disk of material that became the planet.
第二个理论将它们的年纪放到才1亿岁
The second theory puts their age at just 100 million years,
初生牛犊
a relative newborn.
如果恐龙有望远镜 仰望土星的话
If the dinosaurs had telescopes and looked up at Saturn,
那里可能并不存在星环系统
there might not have been a ring system there.
没准比那还新鲜
It's probably much newer than that.
不过我们刚好是幸运儿
But we happen to be the lucky ones
星环在那里 同时
that the rings are there at the same time
我们还拥有望远镜去探索它们
that we have the technology to explore them.
据信土星环是产生于一个灾难性事件
The belief is Saturn's rings were created by a cataclysmic event.
然而它是卫星与小行星之间的剧烈碰撞呢
But was it a massive collision between a moon and an asteroid
还是一股无形的力量将卫星撕成了无数的碎片了呢？
or an invisible force that ripped a moon into billions of pieces?
它们是太阳系里最令人惊叹的结构
They are some of the most awe-inspiring structures in the solar system,
宽度超过22个地球 却只有30英尺厚
wider than 22 Earths while only 30 feet thick.
但是星环猎手所面临的最大谜团
But the biggest mystery facing ring hunters
就是土星环是怎么会出现在那里的
is how Saturn's rings got there.
许多人认为星环诞生于土星的一颗卫星
Many believe that the rings were born when one of Saturn's moons
被一股强大的力量 - 潮汐效应
was ripped to millions or billions of pieces
撕裂成了无数的碎片
by a powerful force called tidal effect.
潮汐效应是普通的引力互动
Tidal effect is any gravitational interaction
就是一侧受到的拉力大于另外一侧
where one side is getting tugged on more than the other side.
如果我有一个巨大的物体就靠在我的这个肩膀旁
So if I had a big, massive object right here closer to this shoulder,
这条肩膀上的拉力就会大于这一条 远方的肩膀
it would pull more on this shoulder than this one, which is further away.
就会把我拉扯开
And it could pull me apart.
在黑洞里 引力极强
In a black hole, where gravity is violently strong,
潮汐效应会扯碎小如人体的物体
tidal effect could pull apart something as small as a human.
你是否听说过词组 - spaghettification
If you've heard the phrase "spaghettification,"
黑洞拉扯你的脚胜过你的头
the black hole is pulling on your feet more than your head,
就会把你拉成长长的意大利面条
and it's stretching you out into a long strand of spaghetti.
在不那么极端的地方 比如我们的太阳系里
In less extreme places, like our solar system,
潮汐效应的影响只有较大的天体才能感受到
the impact of tidal effect is only felt by large bodies
如行星和卫星
like planets and moons.
任何到过海边的人
Anyone who has gone to the seashore
都目睹过月球对地球的潮汐效应
has witnessed the Moon's tidal effect on the Earth.
地球最靠近月球的那部分
The part of the Earth that's nearest to the Moon
被扯向月球要强于地球的远端
gets pulled more strongly toward the Moon than the far side of the Earth.
因此地球会呈现出这种隆起的外观
So the Earth takes on this bulgy appearance
这样你就能看到岸边潮起潮落
so you can see at the shore that the water goes up and down
在大约12个小时的周期里
over a roughly 12-hour period.
然而月球的潮汐效应不仅拉动海洋
But the Moon's tidal effect doesn't only pull the oceans,
它还拉动了整个地球
it pulls the entire planet.
通常没被认识到的就是地球岩石球体本身
Something that's not often recognized is that the rock ball of the planet itself
也会改变形状
changes shape as well.
事实上 地球对着月球方向的直径
In fact, Earth's diameter in the direction toward the Moon
比垂直方向的直径要长出一到两英尺
is a foot or two longer than the diameter in the perpendicular direction,
因为整个地球在月球方向两头被拉伸长了
because the whole Earth is stretched toward and away from the Moon.
行星也会对自己的卫星产生潮汐效应
Planets also have a tidal effect on their moons.
事实上 由于行星大于卫星
In fact, since planets are larger than moons,
它们具有更大的引力 产生更强的潮汐效应
they have more gravity and create stronger tidal effects.
我们月球的成分是岩石和金属
Our Moon is made of rock and metals,
其结实足以对付地球潮汐效应的撕扯
far too solid to be ripped apart by Earth's tidal effect.
但是土星的某些卫星
But some of Saturn's moons
是冰块 尘埃 石头的松散聚集体
were loose conglomerations of ice, dust and rock,
有时就称其为碎石堆
sometimes called rubble piles.
碎石堆可能就像是刨冰之类的东西
A rubble pile might be like a sno-cone or something like this.
你知道的 放在一起是没有牢度的
You know, it's put together with no strength,
除非就是一点表面的张力 - 强度极低的物体
except just little surface forces-- a very low-strength object.
有些科学家认为其中的一颗卫星
Some scientists believe one of these moons
在一亿年前靠土星太近了
strayed too close to Saturn a hundred million years ago.
结合松散的卫星会被撕裂成
The loosely held moon would get ripped apart
数千或数百万个大小不等的碎片
into thousands or millions of pieces of a wide range of sizes,
它们与行星保持着不同的距离
and they would have different distances from the planet
结果就有了不同的轨道
and thus would take on different orbits.
不同轨道的不同周期
The different periods of the different orbits
会逐渐将材料扩散成星环系统
would gradually spread the stuff out into a ring system.
唯有进一步探索才能确定土星环
Only further exploration can determine whether the rings of Saturn
是产生于潮汐效应呢
were created by tidal effect,
卫星的损毁是小行星造成的呢
the destruction of a moon by an asteroid,
还是行星开始形成时所留下的碎片
or from leftover debris when the planet first formed.
不过天文学家最近发现颗粒
But astronomers recently discovered particles
就在他们的眼皮底下加入了星环
joining a ring right before their eyes.
他们发现最外一层环带 E环的
They found that Saturn's outermost band, the E-ring,
存在只是因为土星的一颗卫星叫做恩克拉多斯(土卫二)
only exists because of violent upheavals
的剧烈动荡
on one of Saturn's moons called Enceladus.
这颗引人注目的卫星喷发的是水
What erupts from this extraordinary moon is water.
水从间歇泉里喷出 立刻就冻结了
That water squirts out in geysers and instantly freezes,
有点像滑雪胜地制雪机里的水
kind of like the water in snow-making machines at ski resorts.
这些烟雾状的冰冻颗粒
These plumes of frozen particles
射出卫星地表数百英里
shoot hundreds of miles off the surface of the moon
进入了围绕土星的轨道
where they enter into orbit around Saturn,
形成了E环
and form the E-ring.
除了看到物质加入到土星环之一的兴奋外
Besides the unexpected thrill of seeing material added to one of Saturn's rings,
天文学家还发现了锁定在
astronomers discovered another surprise
E环微观颗粒里的另一个惊喜
locked within the microscopic particles of the E-ring.
2009年6月 科学家发现了微量化学元素
In June 2009, scientists found trace elements of chemicals
俗称的盐和小苏打
commonly known as salt and baking soda.
事情是如此兴奋
The thing that's so exciting about finding
发现了E环中既有盐还有碳酸盐
both the salt and the carbonates in the E-ring is that
那些东西暗示着土卫二内部有液态海洋
those are the kinds of things that suggest a liquid ocean inside of Enceladus.
就像地球上一样 生命诞生于海洋 我们认为
And just like on Earth, where life formed in the oceans, we believe,
有可能真的是生命已经诞生在了土卫二的海洋里了
it could very well be true that life has formed inside of Enceladus.
这是个兴奋不已的契机但是问题根本没有得到解决
This is a really exciting possibility, but it's by no means solved,
因为我们没有看到烟雾中有钠的出现
because we don't see the sodium in the plume coming out.
这些观察提出了一些其他解释
These observations suggest some other explanations.
我们不清楚 我们必须不断去探索
We don't know. We have to keep exploring.
事实上 天文学家每天都源源不断获得
Astronomers are, in fact, getting streams of new data
土星及其星环的新数据流
on Saturn and its rings every day
那是来自1997年发射的航天器 - 卡西尼号
from a spacecraft launched in 1997 called Cassini.
卡西尼号大如一辆小校车
Cassini is about as big as a small school bus.
是航天局历史上打造的最大的星际航天器
It's the biggest interplanetary spacecraft NASA has ever built.
经过七年的航程
After a seven-year journey,
卡西尼号成为了首个进入绕土星轨道的航天器
Cassini became the first spacecraft to enter into an orbit around Saturn,
让人类零距离观察
giving mankind a front-row seat
太阳的第六颗行星及其星环
to the sixth planet from the Sun and its rings.
它已经绕行了土星上百圈
Already it's gone over a hundred times around Saturn.
到任务结束时
By the end of the mission,
它或许会绕土星200圈
It'll probably have gone around Saturn 200 times.
卡西尼号拍摄的图像比以前更加近距离
Cassini has captured images closer than ever before,
揭示了一个变幻莫测的狂野世界
revealing a wild world of shifting forms and surprising variation.
从远处看 它几乎就像是个实体的星环
From a distance, it almost looks like the rings are a solid body,
你知道 就好象是围绕着行星的浩浩荡荡的游行
in, you know, just a sort of stately march around the planet,
但是根本不是那回事
but it's not that way at all.
那是个非常混乱嘈杂的行进
It's a very chaotic, messy process.
研究星环通常的感觉就像是在研究地质
Studying rings used to feel like we were studying geology,
现在的感觉更像是在研究天气
and now it feels more like we're studying the weather.
天文学家惊诧不已的是
To the astonishment of astronomers,
卡西尼号揭示了一个环里的颗粒正在形成一个高耸的波浪
Cassini revealed particles in one ring forming a towering wave.
2009年首次看到 波浪升起在一个星环的边缘
First seen in 2009, the wave rose at the edge of a ring
达到了可怕的高度 超过了一英里
to the terrifying height of more than a mile.
环本身很薄 就30英尺
The rings themselves are very thin, only about 30 feet.
因此就仿佛你在30英尺深的浅湖里
So it's as though you were on a shallow lake only 30 feet deep
有一个一英里高的波浪奔你而来
and then a mile-high wave comes right at you.
真是不得了
It's really remarkable.
这种行星冲浪的肇因原来是一颗卫星的潮汐效应
The cause of this planetary surf turned out to be the gravitational effects
它就是只有5英里宽的达夫尼(木卫三十五)
from a moon just five miles wide named Daphnis.
因为它非常靠近土星的一个环
Because it's so close to one of Saturn's rings,
这颗小卫星的引力
the gravitational pull of this tiny moon
强大到足以引起这种巨大的波浪
is strong enough to create the gigantic waves.
它表明了卫星与星环之间的引力互动
It shows how kind of powerful and remarkable
有多强劲和不同凡响
these gravitational interactions are between the moons and the rings.
这些波浪是卫星将自己标记在环上的唯一途径
These waves are only one way that moons put their mark on rings.
它们也增强了环的形状
They also add to the shapes of the rings,
这样你就看到了间隙 边缘以及环之间清晰的分界
so that you get gaps and edges and very clear divisions between the rings.
产生这些边缘和分界的卫星
Moons that create these edges and divisions
称为护卫卫星
are called shepherd moons.
在土星的F环里 两边都有一颗卫星
In Saturn's F-ring, there's a moon on each side
实际上是把颗粒驱赶进星环
that actually herds the particles into the ring.
这些卫星 普罗米修斯(土卫十六)和潘多拉(土卫十七)
These moons, Prometheus and Pandora,
其实是土星的牛仔
are, in essence, Saturn's cowboys.
它们的工作宛如你在牧场里见到的牛仔
They work just like cowhands you'd find on a ranch.
好 走吧 走
All right, let's go, all right? Let's go get 'em.
我们现在所干的就像是
What we're doing here is much like
土星卫星对待土星环的事
what Saturn's moons do to Saturn's rings.
我们放牧牛群就像是卫星护卫着星环一样
We're herding them just like the moons shepherd the rings.
比如 普罗米修斯和潘多拉放牧着F环
For example, Prometheus and Pandora herd the F-ring.
我就像是普罗米修斯
I'm like Prometheus.
我在内测 我的搭档在外侧
I'm on the inside, and my partner is on the outside.
那就是潘多拉
That's Pandora.
我们让牛群保持一致
And we're keeping these cattle in line
就像卫星让星环保持一致那样
just like the moons keep the rings in line.
卫星与星环颗粒相互作用时
When a moon interacts with a ring particle,
它可以将它踢到较高的轨道上远离土星
it can kick it into a higher orbit further from Saturn
或将其踢进较低的轨道上靠近行星
or kick it into a lower orbit closer to the planet.
潘多拉 距离土星更远些
Pandora, being further from Saturn,
绕行要比环中的颗粒更慢些
orbits more slowly than the particles in the ring.
如果有颗粒离群出走 潘多拉的引力就会拽住它
If a particle strays out, Pandora's gravity pulls on it.
这样就把颗粒的速度放慢 使其跌回到环中
This slows the particle down, causing it to fall back to the ring.
内测 潘多拉的绕行速度
On the inside, Prometheus orbits at a higher speed
快过环中的颗粒
than the ring particles.
其引力拉着它们往前跑 增加它们的能量
Its gravity pulls them forward, increasing their energy
让它们远离土星
and causing them to move away from Saturn.
整体效果是那两颗卫星限制了它们之间的颗粒
The overall effect is that the two moons confine the particles between them,
打造着界限清晰的环
creating a sharply defined ring.
卫星发挥了巨大的作用 根本的作用
The moons play an enormous role, a very fundamental role,
在星环的外貌以及它们的形成过程中
in the way the rings look and how they got formed.
卫星可以护卫环中的颗粒
The moons can shepherd the particles in the rings
这样你就看到了间隙 边缘
so that you get gaps and edges and very clear divisions
以及星环之间清晰的分界
between the rings.
因此星环自始至终完全受控于卫星
So the rings are completely dominated by the moons from the beginning to the end.
土星的闪光带激发了搜寻更多的星环
The glittering bands of Saturn sparked a quest for more rings.
然而它们是数百年里唯一已知的的星环
Yet they were the only known rings for centuries.
星环猎手梦想发现其它星环 怀疑有更多的星环
Ring hunters dreamed of finding others, suspected there were more,
但是没能看到土星那样的东西
and yet could see nothing visible like Saturn's.
随着20世纪的过去
As the 20th century waned,
一个天文学家小组将望远镜对准了天王星
a small team of astronomers focused a telescope on Uranus
希望弄明白它的大气层
in hopes of learning about its atmosphere.
他们根本就不是星环猎手
They weren't ring hunters at all,
但是他们的任务却导致了惊人的启示
and yet their mission led to a shocking revelation,
引发了300多年里星环上最大的发现
triggering the biggest discovery in rings in more than 300 years.
自从伽利略在数百年前发现闪闪发光的土星环以来
Ever since Galileo discovered Saturn's brilliant rings centuries ago,
搜寻更多的星环一直没停过
a quest for more rings was on.
然而几百年过去毫无收获
Yet hundreds of years rolled by without another discovery,
极大挫伤了星环猎手
to the enormous frustration of ring hunters.
到了1977年 一个研究小组
So in 1977, when a small team of researchers
专挑天王星
staked out the planet Uranus,
他们唯一的兴趣就是其大气层
their sole interest was its atmosphere.
3月10日 小组登上一架改进后的飞机
On March 10th, the team flew a modified jet
飞到地球大气层的边缘 将望远镜
to the edge of Earth's atmosphere and trained their telescope
对准了太阳的第七颗行星
on the seventh planet from the Sun.
他们等待着一颗遥远的恒星
They were waiting for the moment
从背后经过天王星的那一刻
when a distant star would pass behind Uranus.
他们测量了恒星从背后穿过行星
They were measuring the brightness of a star as a function of time
亮度的时间变量
as it was going to pass behind the planet.
这样 你就可以研究行星大气层的结构了
And in this way you can study the structure of the atmosphere of the planet.
然而在恒星接近时 奇怪的事情发生了
But as the star approached Uranus, something strange happened.
在它走到天王星的背后之前
Before it went behind Uranus,
星光实际上闪烁了几次
the light actually blinked out several times.
傻了眼的科学家等待着观察恒星从另一侧
Stunned scientists waited to see what would happen
出现时会发生些什么
when the star reappeared on the other side.
在其从天王星背后露脸时
And then after emerging from behind Uranus,
它同样也闪烁了几次
it blinked out several times as well.
研究小组发现了完全出乎意料的东西
The team had discovered something completely unexpected.
行星一侧的闪烁完全对称在了另外一面的那些地方
The dips on one side of the planet were perfectly symmetrical to those on the other.
这意味着他们发现了带有星环的第二颗行星
It meant they had found a second planet with rings.
那是个惊喜
That was a surprise,
第一次看到时激动不已
and it was very exciting to see for the first time.
那是300多年里首个新发现的星环系统
It was the first new ring system discovered in more than 350 years,
它会一发不可收拾
and it would open the floodgates.
两个多环系统很快就被发现了
Two more ring systems would soon be discovered,
一个在遥远的海王星 一个在最大的行星- 木星
one on distant Neptune and one on the largest planet, Jupiter.
我们现在知道我们太阳系里有四颗行星有星环
So we now know that four planets in our solar system have rings.
事实上 围绕太阳的四颗最大的行星都有星环系统
And, in fact, all four of the giant planets orbiting the Sun have ring systems.
但如果星环是普遍的
But if rings are common,
那为何天文学家花了这么长的时间才发现其他的呢？
why did it take astronomers so long to find the others?
因为其他行星的环完全不同于土星环
Because the rings of the other planets are quite different than Saturn's.
绝非偶然的
It wasn't by accident that
土星环在17世纪初发现时
Saturn's rings were discovered back at the beginning of the 17th century
其他星环系统均未发现 直到20世纪的尾声
and no other ring system was found until near the end of the 20th century.
土星环宽阔 明亮 壮观
Saturn's rings are broad, they're bright, they're spectacular.
其他系统要细微得多
The other systems are much more subtle.
细微部分是因为它们的大小
Subtle in part because of their size.
天王星环所发现的一个惊人的模样
A very surprising aspect of the discovery of Uranus' rings
就是它们非常狭窄
was that they're very narrow.
大部分土星环有数千英里宽
Most of Saturn's rings are thousands of miles wide.
相比之下 多数天王星环
By comparison, the majority of Uranus' rings
覆盖不足两英里
cover less than two miles.
其他部分则是非常昏暗
The other part is that they're very, very dark,
而土星环是冰块构成的 因而非常明亮
whereas the rings of Saturn are made of ice and they're very bright.
想想比沥青还黑的东西
Think about something much darker than tar.
它们漆黑一片 无与伦比
They're as black as anything you can probably see.
尤其是 天王星最外层的环极其昏暗
What's more, the outermost rings of Uranus are so dim,
星环猎手一直没有发现它们 直到2003年
ring hunters didn't find them until 2003.
这主要是因为其中几乎空无一物
This is largely because there is almost nothing in them.
整个系统里是非常微弱的尘埃云
Throughout the system there's clouds of very faint dust
这种填充系数是十万分之一或百万分之一的水平
at this level of a filling factor of one in 100,000 or one in a million.
这些颗粒相互之间间隔遥远
These particles are spaced so far away from each other,
它就像是宇宙赛道
it would be like a cosmic racetrack
从地球伸展到月球再折回
that stretched from the Earth to the Moon and back,
只有寥寥无几的汽车在上面跑
and it would have just a handful of cars on it.
它完全不同于土星环
it's a radical difference from Saturn's rings,
那里通常是颗粒相互挤在一起
where particles are often packed in side by side,
保险杠顶到保险杠
bumper to virtual bumper.
天王星外环极其稀疏
The outer rings of Uranus are extremely sparse,
但它们并非最昏暗的
but they are not the faintest.
该奖项归于太阳第五颗行星最外面的环
That award goes to the outermost bands around the fifth planet from the Sun.
强大的木星拥有最微弱的星环
Mighty Jupiter has the most delicate rings of all.
迄今为止 天文学家已经确定了有四个缥缈的星环围绕着这颗行星
So far, astronomers have identified four ethereal rings circling the planet:
内环 主环 两个外环
an inner ring, the main ring, and two outer rings.
不同于土星环里所看到的大过汽车的冰块
Unlike the icy chunks bigger than a car found in Saturn's rings,
木星环里的颗粒主要是最细的尘埃般大小
the particles in the rings of Jupiter are mainly the size of the finest dust.
我们经常把这些说是尘埃环
We often refer to these as dust rings,
但更佳的说法是烟雾环
but the better word would be smoke rings.
颗粒都是微米级的
The particles are microns in size.
火产生的烟基本上就是微米级的
Smoke coming off of a fire is basically microns in size.
星环 如这颗行星的 巨大无比
The rings, like the planet, are mammoth,
绵延近直径30万英里
sprawling nearly 300,000 miles in diameter.
然而难以置信的是 如果你将所有的颗粒压缩成一个球
Yet incredibly, if you squashed all the particles into a single ball,
它不会宽过一个足球场
it would be no wider than a football field
甚至会小到就一攻的距离
and perhaps as small as the distance of a first down.
两个最外层的环极其微弱
There is so little in the two outermost bands
是我们太阳系里所见到的最昏暗的环
that they are the faintest rings ever detected in our solar system.
几乎看不见 它们被称为薄纱光环
Almost invisible, they are called the Gossamer Rings.
你可以实际坐在木星的薄纱光环里
You could actually sit inside the Gossamer Ring of Jupiter
甚至都不知道它就在那里
and not even know it was there.
我的意思是 也许你在尘埃微粒碰到你的宇航服时
I mean, maybe you'd hear an occasional ping
偶尔会听到砰的一声
on your spacesuit as a dust particle came by,
但你看不到任何东西
but you would not see anything.
虽然木星环微弱得难以置信
As impossibly faint as the bands of Jupiter are,
但搜索海王星环
it was the search for rings around Neptune
被证明是对星环猎手最大的挑战
that proved the most challenging for ring hunters.
海王星在1980年代被怀疑有星环
Neptune was suspected to have rings in the 1980s
当时这些区域里的物质遮挡了行将
when the material in these regions blocked the light of a star
从背后越过行星球面的一颗恒星的光线
that was about to go behind the ball of the planet.
利用发现天王星环同样的技术
Using the same technique that had detected the rings of Uranus,
天文学家尝试了约50次试图发现海王星环
astronomers tried some 50 times to find the rings of Neptune.
结果让人沮丧 无功而返
The results were maddeningly inconclusive.
被激怒的科学家提出了一个激进的解释
Exasperated scientists proposed a radical explanation.
由于星光偶尔受阻
Since starlight was occasionally blocked,
或许海王星旁边的奇怪的星环
perhaps there were strange rings around Neptune
仅仅是部分包围着该行星
that only partially encircled the planet.
我们不认为它们是完整的星环
We didn't think that they were complete rings,
因为阻挡行星两边的星光并非
because the blocking of light on either side of the planet was not symmetrical
天王星环那样是对称的
the way it was for the rings of Uranus.
难道海王星具有某种离奇突变的星环系统？
Could it be that Neptune had some bizarre and mutant ring system?
星环猎手从未下过如此决心去揭开这个谜团
Ring hunters had never been so determined to solve the mystery,
他们无法预料解决之道会有多离谱
and they had no way to anticipate how bizarre that solution would be.
350多年来 唯一所知的星环
For more than 350 years, the only known rings
就是土星明亮耀眼的光带
were the bright and dazzling bands of Saturn.
然而 在短短的两年时间里 从1977年开始
Then, in a space of just two years, starting in 1977,
两组新的星环被发现了 -
two new sets of rings were discovered--
一个在天王星 另一个在木星
one on Uranus, the other on Jupiter.
但是搜索遥远的海王星环
But the search for rings around distant Neptune
却拖延了令人沮丧的N多年
dragged on for many more frustrating years.
海王星极其遥远
Neptune is very, very far away.
它远离太阳
It's a great distance from the Sun,
因此星环没有太多的亮度
and therefore there's not much illumination on the ring.
此外 从未有过航天器造访过海王星直到1989年
In addition to that, no spacecraft went by Neptune until 1989
航天局的旅行者二号才造访了我们太阳系的这最后一颗行星
when Voyager II from NASA went by the last planet in our solar system.
旅行者二号是天文学家搜索星环最好的武器
Voyager II was the astronomers' best weapon in the hunt for rings.
在1989年8月25日 该航天器接近海王星
On August 25, 1989, the spacecraft got as close to Neptune
达到了所有人造飞船从未有过的距离
as any manmade craft ever would.
它拍摄到了星环猎手们所见到的
It captured the best images ring hunters had seen
太阳第八行星的最佳图像 堪称惊人的技术壮举
of the eighth planet from the Sun, an incredible technological feat.
那是个挑战
It was a challenge.
就像是拍摄煤仓里的黑猫照片
It was like taking a picture of a cat in a coal bin
在月光这样的条件下 知道吗
under moonlight or something, you know.
那么它们会揭示出海王星没有星环
So would they reveal that Neptune had no rings,
还是完整的星环 还是神秘的不完整环
full rings, or the mysterious partial rings
就是某些天文学家所提出的那样？
that some astronomers had proposed?
在旅行者任务前的十多年里
For more than a decade before the Voyager mission,
科学家试图利用从背后越过
scientists had tried to detect rings
海王星的各种星光来发现星环
using the light of various stars passing behind Neptune.
某些尝试看到了星光的衰减
Some attempts saw dips in starlight,
但是它们从来不是在同样的距离上
but they were never at the same distance
在行星的两侧好像有完整的星环存在
on both sides of the planet like full rings would be.
海王星让人恼怒不已
Neptune was exasperating.
我们知道那里有东西存在
We knew there was stuff there.
但是我们不知道其形态如何
But we didn't know what the configuration was.
因此当旅行者的图像源源不断发回时星环猎手激动不已
So when images from Voyager rolled in, ring hunters were thrilled.
不仅是个完整的环
Not only were there complete rings,
而且环中还有某些从未见到过的东西 - 弧
but there was something in the rings that had never been seen before: arcs.
最重要的特色就是一组星弧
The most prominent feature are a set of arcs,
它只占围绕行星的轨道不足10分之一
which only go less than a tenth of the way around the planet.
环的其余部分则虚无缥缈
The rest of the ring, very ethereal.
弧只是星环中
Arcs were simply segments of a ring that
比其余部分更亮更稠密的片段
were brighter and thicker than the rest of the ring.
星环其余部分少的可怜的物质
The incredibly small amount of material in the rest of the ring
解释了为何天文学家从地球上
explained why astronomers had not been able to detect
一直未能发现有完整的星环
the complete rings from Earth.
弧存在于一个完整的环里
The arcs lie within a full ring,
但这个完整的环里的物质几乎是透明的
but the matter in this full ring is almost transparent.
所以我们以前在观察阻挡星光中从未见到过它
So we couldn't ever see it before with watching it block starlight.
海王星环的发现意味着
The discovery of rings around Neptune meant
所有的气体巨型外行星都带有星环
that all of the gas giant outer planets had rings.
那是宇宙自然秩序的一个折射
It was a reflection of the natural order of the cosmos,
因为星环的圆盘状
because the disk shape of rings
是宇宙间最原始的形态之一
is one of the most primordial forms in the universe.
宇宙包括了天体的两种基本蓝本
The universe contains two sort of fundamental blueprints for objects,
就是球状和碟状
and those are spheres and disks.
如果旋转是天体结构的重要表现方式
If spin is a really important aspect of an object's structure,
那么它往往会形成碟状
then it will tend to form into a disk,
因而我们就看到宇宙间的大小不等的碟状
and so we see disks on every scale in the universe.
那就是为什么土星环
This is why the rings of Saturn
能够告诉我们一个大得更多的环系统的起源
can tell us about the origins of a much bigger ring system:
围绕我们太阳的那个
the one around our Sun.
土星环是行星形成过程的一个蓝本
Saturn's rings are a blueprint for the processes that give rise to planet formation.
如果我们回到过去
If we were to go back in time
访问我们45亿年前的太阳系
and visit our own solar system 4 1/2 billion years ago,
年轻的太阳就已经坐镇中央了
the young Sun would've been at the center,
它被气体和尘埃盘团团围住
and it would've been surrounded by a disk of gas and dust,
气体和尘埃盘
and that disk of gas and dust
将会有行星在其中形成
would have had planets forming inside of it,
整个星盘看上去 一定程度上
and that whole disk would have looked, to a certain extent,
就像是个星环系统
like a system of rings.
最早的行星开始诞生于碎片盘里
The first planets began to form in the debris disk.
在它们的长大过程中 它们的引力清理出了轨道上的空间
As they grew larger, their gravity cleared out space in their orbits.
在它们引力影响范围内的碎片
Debris that was within their gravitational influence
被添加或被击出到了太空里
was added on or whipped out into space.
这就是木星形成时 我们太阳系里所发生的情况
This is exactly what happened in our own solar system when Jupiter formed,
因为木星的个头足以在我们的星盘里清理出一个豁口
because Jupiter was massive enough to clear a gap in our own disk.
一段时间后 我们太阳系里的其他行星形成了
In time, the other planets in our solar system formed
清理出了各自的轨道 只为碎片留下了两个空间
and cleared out their own orbits, leaving just two spaces for debris:
小行星带和柯伊伯带
the asteroid belt and the Kuiper belt.
它们共同创造了相当于一组庞大的星环围绕着太阳
Together they create what amounts to a vast set of rings around the Sun.
作为我们太阳系的蓝本
As a blueprint of our solar system,
星环帮助我们了解了我们自身的起源
rings help us understand our own beginnings.
然而星环猎手长期以来孜孜以求最大的奖项之一
Yet ring hunters have long wanted to pursue one of the biggest prizes of all:
其它太阳系里的环状行星
ringed planets in other solar systems.
我们已经知道有许多行星 个头类似于土星
We already know of many planets that have masses similar to Saturn,
成分类似于土星
and composition similar to Saturn,
十有八九 不是它们全部
and it's a good bet that not all of them,
而是其中的一些 会有壮观的星环系统
but some of them, have spectacular ring systems.
他们现在相信他们不久就能在别的太阳系里
They now believe they'll discover the first ringed planet
发现首个环状行星 借助于
from another solar system very soon with the help
世上最强大的望远镜之一 - 开普勒
of one of the world's most powerful telescopes, Kepler.
开普勒能够一次跟踪约10万颗恒星
Kepler is able to track about 100,000 stars at a time.
它被打造成能测量星光中最微小的变化
It was designed to measure the tiniest changes in starlight,
因而它可以侦测出从恒星面前经过的遥远的行星
so that it could detect distant planets that pass in front of a star.
一旦发生那样的事情 行星就会挡住一点点星光
When that happens, the planet blocks out a little bit of the star's light,
开普勒就可以侦测到其衰变
and Kepler can detect that dip.
如果有环状行星正面经过恒星
If a ringed planet goes in front of a star,
星环也会阻挡星光
then the rings also block out the star's light,
其信号也能被开普勒测量到
and that signal can be measured by Kepler as well.
在开普勒注视宇宙期间
While Kepler gazes deep into the universe,
天文学家也在搜索我们自己的太阳系里的新的星环
astronomers are also hunting for a new ring within our own solar system.
4  3  2  1  0
4, 3, 2, 1, 0
2006年 一艘叫做新地平线号的飞船飞离了发射台
In 2006, a mission called New Horizons roared off the launch pad.
27亿英里的航程
Its 2.7 billion-mile journey
将带其前往冰冷的太阳系边缘
will take it to the frozen edge of the solar system.
如果它能挺过 将会成为飞经冥王星的首个航天器
If it survives, it will become the first spacecraft to fly past Pluto.
天文学家怀疑这颗矮行星
Astronomers suspect that the dwarf planet
也许是能找到有星环的首个岩石天体
may be the first rocky object found to have rings,
然而我们太阳系里还有另一颗环状行星
yet there is another ringed planet in our solar system.
其星环处在带来灾难的碰撞行程中
Its ring is on a collision course with disaster,
有可能会导致对地球的骚扰
which could lead to chaos on Earth.
我们太阳系的四颗外行星
The four outer planets of our solar system
全都环绕有星环
are all encircled by rings,
有些绚丽多彩 有些尘土飞扬 有些微弱无光
some dazzling, some dusty, some remarkably faint.
然而探索再次对准了最为遥远的对象
Yet the quest is on for one more, the most distant of all,
它围绕着寒冷的石头 - 冥王星
encircling a frigid rock called Pluto.
一度被认为是名副其实的行星
Once considered to be a genuine planet,
它在2006年被重新分类为矮行星
it was reclassified as a dwarf planet in 2006.
到2015年 它有可能成为我们太阳系里发现有
In 2015, it may become the newest member of our solar system
星环的最新成员
found to have rings.
冥王星可能带有星环 很昏暗的星环
Pluto might have rings, very faint rings,
或许有朝一日会获得星环 因为冥王星所处的地带
or may someday gain rings, because Pluto is in a region
有大量的彗星在到处游荡
where there are lots of comets floating around.
一旦其中的一个靠近冥王星
And if one of them gets close to Pluto,
就可能被冥王星的引力吸引破坏
it might get tidally shattered by Pluto's gravity,
暂时形成了星环
temporarily forming a ring.
新地平线号
A mission called New Horizons
已经走过了与冥王星会合的三分之一的路程
is already a third of the way to a rendezvous with Pluto.
它在2015年传回的图像
The images it transmits in 2015
将会揭示这颗遥远的矮行星是否具有星环
should reveal if the distant dwarf has rings.
然而星环猎手最近预计找到新的星环系统会近很多
Yet ring hunters recently expected to find a new ring system much closer,
就在地球最近的邻居 - 火星那里
on Earth's nearest neighbor, Mars.
长期以来一直有猜测 火星可能具有一个星环系统
There's long been speculation that Mars might have a ring system.
那实际上要回到上世纪70年代
It goes actually back to the 1970s.
部分推断就在于我们看太阳系到处
And part of the reasoning now is that everywhere we look in the solar system
都能看到有小卫星
that we see small satellites,
有微弱的星环与它们相关
there is a faint ring associated with them.
两颗小卫星围绕着火星
Two small satellites, or moons, orbit Mars.
尽管每个都不足20英里宽
Though each is less than 20 miles wide,
但是天文学家认为有足够的尘埃掉离这些小卫星形成微弱的星环
astronomers believed enough dust came off these moons to form a faint ring.
它们必定会产生尘埃云
They must be producing clouds of dust.
我们知道毫无疑问 唯一的问题就在于
We know that for certain, and the only question is
它们何时以及如何形成一个环？
when and how does that form into a ring?
然而 当他们在21世纪将强大的哈勃望远镜
Yet, when they trained the powerful Hubble Telescope
对准火星时 一无所获
on Mars in the 21st century, they saw nothing.
我们现在已观察过了两遍 我们啥都没看到
We've looked twice now, and we have not seen anything.
因而我们开始有点困惑了
So we're beginning to get a little bit puzzled
为何火星没有星环呢
as to why there are no rings of Mars.
地球本身曾经有过星环
The Earth itself once had a ring.
炽热的巨大石块曾呼啸在地球周围
Giant chunks of red hot rock whizzed around the planet
至少有过一些年头 然后就消失了
for at least a few years and then vanished.
怎么回事呢？
How could that have been?
45亿年前 当时地球刚刚形成
4 1/2 billion years ago, when the Earth had just formed,
一颗火星般大的巨大天体撞上了我们的星球
a giant body the size of Mars smashed into our planet.
形成了一个临时的星环 其壮观绝对胜过
And that formed a temporary ring that was even more spectacular
今日的土星环
than Saturn's is today,
一定意义上 它不仅是个庞大而厚重的星环
in the sense that it was not just a big, thick ring,
十分巨大 而且它红彤彤一片
very massive, but it was glowing red hot.
随着熔岩的冷却
As the molten rock cooled,
部分被抛回地球 部分飞入了太空
some was thrown back to Earth and some flew out into space.
其余材料凝结成了一个球体 形成了我们的月球
The rest of the material condensed into a sphere that became our Moon.
不过地球人没必要感到被排除在外了
But Earthlings don't need to feel left out.
我们的地球家园有了一个新的环 那才50年历史
Our home planet has a new ring, and this one is just 50 years old.
其构成不是尘埃或冰岩 而是金属和硅
It's not made of dust or icy rock, but metals and silicon.
那是卫星构成的环
It's a ring of satellites.
地球本身已经打造了
The Earth has built itself
一个高科技的复杂的卫星环
a highly technologically complicated ring of satellites
将会维持数百万年
that will last for millions of years.
由约400颗卫星构成
Comprised of some 400 satellites,
它是已知由宇宙中的生命创造的星环
it's the only known ring created by life in the universe.
它盘旋在地球赤道上方2 2万英里的
It hovers 22,000 miles above the Earth's equator
地球同步轨道上 在那里 它们的速度将它们
in a geosynchronous orbit, where their speed will hold them
长期固定在地球上方的同一个地方
in exactly the same spot over the planet indefinitely.
地球同步卫星
The geosynchronous satellites
是这种非常特殊的卫星种类
are this very special sort of subcategory of satellites,
它们围绕地球形成了一个真正的星环
and they form a true ring around the Earth.
星环一定意义上是在轨运行的颗粒
And it's a ring in the sense that they are orbiting particles
在不断落向地球
that are continuously falling around the Earth,
很像土星环那样
much the same way as Saturn's rings,
颗粒状冰粒全都在不停地落向土星
gravel-like icy particles that are all falling around Saturn.
地球环是人类通讯的重要组成部分
Earth's ring is a critical component to human communications,
但是它也在导向灾难
but it's heading for disaster.
我们在星环研究中得知
What we know in ring studies
如果你将足够的物体放在一个地方
is that if you put enough things in one place
它们就会发生碰撞
then they're gonna start colliding.
事实上 在2009年2月
In fact, in February of 2009,
两颗低轨道卫星就发生了碰撞
two satellites in a low-Earth orbit did collide.
撞击震惊了全世界的政府
The crash sent shockwaves through governments
和科学界
and the scientific community around the world.
我们看到两颗大卫星撞击在了一起
We had two large satellites and they collided.
它们撞得粉身碎骨
They blew themselves to smithereens.
我们现在或许有上万个物体
And we now have maybe 10,000 objects,
全都围绕着地球
all in orbit around the Earth.
它们全都是子弹
Each of those is a bullet,
每个的速度或许都在每秒10英里
and each of those is moving perhaps at 10 miles per second,
其中的任何一个都有能力
and any one of those has the capacity
在另一次撞击过程中抹去另一颗卫星
to take out another satellite should another collision occur.
地球同步轨道上的每一颗新卫星
Each new satellite in the geosynchronous orbit
就像是在赛道上增加了一辆赛车
is like adding a race car to the track.
每一个都增加了碰撞的危险
Every one increases the danger of a collision.
如果两两相撞 飞出的碎片将破坏整个星环
If two collide, the flying debris could destroy the entire ring,
使地球上的通讯陷入混乱
throwing communications on Earth into chaos.
最终 它就只会是放啥都不安全的地方
Eventually, it will just be an unsafe place to put anything
因为你会看到枪林弹雨一刻不停
because you've got swarms of bullets flying past you all the time.
无论是人造的还是天然的
Whether artificial or natural,
星环猎手坚持寻求珍贵的光带
ring hunters continue to pursue the prized bands,
因为它们是宇宙间最基本的形态之一
because they're one of the most essential forms of the universe.
没有它们不停地旋转形成星系 太阳系 行星
Without them spinning into galaxies, solar systems, and planets,
我们熟知的生命将不会存在
life as we know it would not exist.
星环 原来是希望的起点
Rings, it turns out, are the beginning of what is possible.
确实 我们跑出数十亿英里试图去看看外面的世界
It is true that we go billions of miles out to try to see what's out there,
然而也就是因为它让我们明白 我们是如何形成的
but it's because it tells us how we formed,
我们的后院是啥模样 我们的太阳系是啥模样
what our own backyard is like, what our solar system is like.
我们了解其他世界的情况愈多
If we learn more about what's possible in other worlds,
我们对地球的认识就愈深
we learn more about what's possible here on earth.